Mauaa Datta



4+91 91767 22453

Summary

I am a seasoned front-end developer with around 5 years industry experience who loves to bring visual design to live. I enjoy building beautiful and functional web applications.

My skill set includes HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript and Angular. I have gained expertise in responsive design. With every line of code, I try to make application livelier and more interactive.

Experience



Senior Frontend Developer

Koder

Jun 2019 - Present (1 year 9 months +)

Koder is a future-of-work platform that connects companies with teams of crowdsourced developers to deliver results. Through the Koder service, anyone can get an elite team of engineers to build their next idea, meticulously managed by a Silicon Valley or LA-based Product Manager and CTO. Key Responsibilities:

- 1. Worked on building a learning portal called 'U' which allows different instructors to create free/paid courses and teach students. Students can find a variety of courses to enroll.
- Worked on building complete responsive pages
- Involved in writing SQL queries and integrating backend with frontend
- Got exposure to data-scrapping using Octoparse
- Worked on enabling stripe enabled payment gateway
- Technologies/Tools: HTML5, SCSS, jQuery, C#, Razor, Octoparse
- 2. Worked for US based payment platform for users
- Worked on building complete responsive pages
- Technologies/Tools: HTML5, SCSS, jQuery, Gulp
- 3. Worked for building admin portal for Koder
- Integrating REST APIs with components using angular and typescript
- Make shareable and reusable components
- Creating HTML for the given visual designs



Sr UI/UX Developer

Digitate

Apr 2017 - Jun 2019 (2 years 3 months)

Ignio by Digitate is a Tata Consultancy Services venture, an Al based enterprise solution. I have been working as Sr UI developer responsible to translate the design templates into cross platform web application.

https://www.digitate.com/

Key Responsibilities:

Enabling webpack and its plugins for boosting performance

- Integrating REST APIs with components using angular and typescript
- Make shareable and reusable components
- · Carving out widgets with maximum defaults and minimum inputs
- Providing mixins, utilities and properties with help of SASS
- Creating HTML for the given visual designs
- Actively discussing design ideas with UX team to enhance user experience Business Impact:
- Applied concepts of RWD for the application
- Optimised the CSS resulting in 30% faster loading of application
- Applied optimisation techniques for HTML and Images which brought down the bundle size by 20%
- Created a customer experience and product briefing center with interactive graphics

tcs UI Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

Jul 2014 - Mar 2017 (2 years 9 months)

https://www.tcs.com/

Worked for Latin America based e-commerce website

Responsibilities:

- Creating HTML for the given visual designs
- Coordinating with the onsite team about the requirements and deliverable

Building website for NSDC

Responsibilities:

- Being involved in requirement gathering and design discussions
- Groomed a team of 24 trainees to learn and develop district wise web portals for NSDC

Education



Mumbai University Mumbai

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology

2011 - 2014

Created a web application for a jewellery retailer with ASP .net with C# and SQL

Created a business portfolio for a Fountain and Swimming pool business as a freelancer



CHM College Mumbai

HSC, PCMB

2009 - 2011

Licenses & Certifications



Angular 4 - Lynda.com

Backbone.js foundation - Lynda.com

Skills

HTML5 • css3 • Bootstrap • Angular • SASS • JavaScript • TypeScript • jQuery • RWD • Bootstrap • Materialize • css3

Honors & Awards

Star Performer - TCS

2018

Awarded star performer for creating the customer briefing center under stringent timelines

Short Story Writer - TCS Maitree Club

2017

Stood winner for short story writing contest. https://mauaadatta.blogspot.com/

Topper in College - Birla College 2014